<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supports on SLU RCG Website</title>
    <link>/research-computing-group/support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supports on SLU RCG Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/research-computing-group/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Application Installation</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/application-installation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/application-installation/</guid>
      <description>Application Installation Applications can be installed in your home directory. Your home directory is stored on a network share. So, that application is able to run on individual nodes. We can also install applications and environment modules for them. This will allow anyone on the cluster to use the application without having to install it. Documentation for using environment modules is below.
Environment Modules We are using Environment Modules Package on Kepler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compilers</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/compilers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/compilers/</guid>
      <description>We have several compiler environments on the cluster. Many are interdependent.
GCC The preferred and default compiler on the cluster is GCC, the GNU Compiler Chain.
The MPI compiler chain A wrapper around GCC for compiling programs for use in an MPI environment.
Here are some example commands:
Say there’s a file in a folder named chug.c. From that folder in the command line try the command ‘make chug’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infiniband</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/infiniband/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/infiniband/</guid>
      <description>InfiniBand is a switched fabric communications link that is used in high-performance computing. For more detailed information visit the Wikipedia page.
This is available on the nodes listed below. These nodes have access to the /mnt/xfs network share. This is space large file storage and scratch space on the nodes. All users have rights to create directories on this share. Please note that /mnt/xfs is not backed up on a nightly basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Versions of Python</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/python-versions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/python-versions/</guid>
      <description>There are a few reasons you may need a different version of Python. You may need a newer version of Python or need multiple modules installed. This can be accomplished with pyenv.
This can be installed in your /home directory by following the instructions below.
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Cut and paste the following code to your command prompt.
curl -L https://raw.github.com/yyuu/pyenv-installer/master/bin/pyenv-installer | bash  2.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Add the code listed below to your .bashrc file. Type nano .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Language</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/r-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/r-language/</guid>
      <description>We currently have modules for R 3.0.0, R 3.1.2, and R 3.2.0
Installing Modules
Starting command line R
Just type R at the command prompt.
Common Commands
   library() - This will show what libraries are currently installed on kepler   .libPaths() - This shows you the paths to the installed libraries   q() - Quits the current R sesison.    
Parallel R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Jobs on the Cluster</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/running-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/running-cluster/</guid>
      <description>Running Applications on Apex
Most of the jobs on Apex will be run via the scheduler SLURM. The scheduler will take care of most of the logistics of where the job is run etc.
If you are new to SLURM, the SLURM 101 tutorial is a good place to start. This will show you how to write a basic job script and submit it to the scheduler. Partitions:
A partition is the same thing as a job queue on Apex.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS, SPSS, and ATLAS.ti</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/sas-spss-atlas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/sas-spss-atlas/</guid>
      <description>These powerful analytic programs have been made available for faculty and students by Saint Louis University
SAS
Available for university purposes on University-owned or personal machines
Each computer will need its own yearly subscription:  The subscription runs from July 1 to June 30 the following year For July 1, 2014 – June 30, 2015, regardless of your actual date of purchase, the price is $95 For departmental purchases&amp;hellip; payment of the $95 license can be made through eSeeIDO under the &amp;ldquo;Finance&amp;rdquo; tab in Banner Upon proper receipt of the request, ITS will install or update the SAS license on the requested computer More information can be found here: https://sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/support/storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/support/storage/</guid>
      <description>Your home directory is backed up nightly on kepler. Currently, we don&amp;rsquo;t impose a disk quota. There are many users on both systems and we do have limited space, so we ask that you delete files that you are not using.
There is space on kepler for large file storage and scratch space on the nodes. The path to the space is /mnt/xfs/ and /xfs2 . You can create your own directory there.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>