<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting-starteds on SLU RCG Website</title>
    <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting-starteds on SLU RCG Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/research-computing-group/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FTP</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/ftp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/getting-started/ftp/</guid>
      <description>File Transfer Protocol (FTP) is a standard network protocol used to copy a file from one host to another over a TCP/IP-based network, such as the Internet. FTP is built on a client-server architecture and utilizes separate control and data connections between the client and server. FTP users may authenticate themselves using a clear-text sign-in protocol, but they can connect anonymously if the server is configured to allow it.
One of the easiest FTP applications to use if FileZilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/getting-started/ssh/</guid>
      <description>SSH is a secure protocol that allows you to connect to a remote system. In order to access a HPC cluster from off-campus, you will need Billiken Secure Connect VPN account. More information can be found here BIlliken Secure Connect (VPN).
Note: There is also a graphical user interface that can be used with the cluster. See the VNC section for more information.
Common Linux Commands
Once you have logged into an HPC, you are communicating to a completely text-based Linux environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vpn/</guid>
      <description>VPN stands for virtual private network. This allows you to make a securely connect to campus resources when you are not on campus.
In order to access the HPC cluster off campus, you will need a Billiken Secure Connect VPN account.
VPN information and account request can be found here Billiken VPN.
Note: In order to get a student account, permission will be needed from the department chair.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vnc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vnc/</guid>
      <description>VNC allows you to use the cluster with a graphical user interface. Detailed information can be found on Wikipedia VNC page.
Before you can use VNC you will need to set up a VNC session on the head node. All VNC sessions also require a ssh tunnel. This is for security purposes. The TightVNC Client will create the tunnel and VNC login in one step. Instructions for this are below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNC Subpage</title>
      <link>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vnc_subpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research-computing-group/getting-started/vnc_subpage/</guid>
      <description>VNC allows you to use a graphical user interface on the cluster.
See the following VNC documentation for basic setup. There are a few additional steps that will need to be completed to set up VNC.
If you want to use VNC, you will first need to do the following.
1.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;First, you will need to ssh to the server with a ssh client. See the ssh documentation for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>